哪里有不幸
哪里就有上帝派来的狗
拉马丁
《狗 神》
字幕:Dex7er 公众号:值得看的
纽瓦克
新泽西花园州
Evening, ma'am.
晚上好, 女士
Your ID and the vehicle's registration, please.
请出示身份证和车辆登记证
I'm sorry, officer.
对不起, 警官
I left it in the dash, and I don't have anything with me.
我出来得太急, 什么都没带
I just plumb forgot.
我就是全忘了
Okay, ma'am, I'll need you to get out while we search your truck.
好的, 女士, 请你下车, 我们要搜查你的卡车
Oh, I wouldn't do that if I were you.
哦, 如果我是你, 就不会这么做
What the fuck is this?
这是什么鬼东西？
Ma'am, hands up where I can see them.
女士, 把手放在我能看见的地方
They won't hurt you as long as you don't hurt me.
只要你们不伤害我, 它们就不会伤害你们
Ma'am, put your hands on the dashboard now.
女士, 把手放在仪表盘上
Ma'am, are you listening to me?
女士, 你在听我说话吗？
You got a light, officer?
你有打火机吗 警官？
Hello?
喂？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
It's 2 o'clock in the morning.
现在是凌晨两点
Hey, Ma, I have to go.
嘿 妈 我得走了
What's going on?
怎么了？
There's an emergency at the detention center.
拘留中心有紧急情况
Why do they always have to call you for these shitty jobs?
为什么他们一有这些烂活总是来找你？
I take what they give me.
我从不挑肥拣瘦
Isn't that right?
对不对？
It's too much.
太多了
Ma'am, can I help you?
女士, 需要帮忙吗？
Yes, sir.
是的,警官
I'm here for the suspect that just arrived.
我来见刚到的那个嫌犯
Here?
这里？
In the pink dress.
粉色裙子的那个
Oh, yeah.
哦, 对
This one.
这个
Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢谢
Odtiaľ, ma'am
这边来 女士
I'm going to stay behind the door, just in case.
我就呆在门后, 以防万一
Thank you.
谢谢
Hello.
你好
I'm Dr. Evelyn Decker.
我是艾芙琳·戴克医生
May I ask your name?
请问你叫什么名字？
Besides the fact that smoking is bad for your health, I must remind you
除了吸烟有害健康之外, 我还必须提醒你
that it is quite simply illegal to smoke on the premises.
在这里吸烟是违法的
Does it bother you?
会打扰到你吗？
Not really.
其实不会
Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢谢
Actually, I'm sorry that you wasted your time.
事实上, 我很遗憾浪费了你的时间
I'm not sick.
我没病
I'm just tired.
我只是累了
I'm a psychiatrist, to be more specific.
更确切地说, 我是一名精神科医生
I'm here because my colleagues are struggling to get a handle on you.
我来这里, 是因为我的同事们很头疼, 不知如何处理你的情况
They don't quite know which aisle to put you in,
他们不知道该把你关在哪一边
so they would like to know who you are.
所以他们想知道你是谁
They don't blame me.
这不怪他们
But I always liked disguises.
但我一直喜欢装扮
That's what you do when you don't really know who you are, right?
当你也不清楚自己是谁时, 你就会这样, 对吧？
You dress up, you make up a past to forget your own.
装扮自己, 编个故事, 忘记自己的过去
Is dressing up equal lying to yourself, Doctor?
装扮自己等同于自欺欺人吗, 医生？
Depends.
看情况
Generally, a disguise is used to conceal what we don't want to see.
一般来说, 装扮是用来掩盖我们不想看到的事实
That's interesting.
这很有趣
I always thought there was a way of becoming someone else.
我一直以为有一种方法可以让你变成另外一个人
It'd be very pleasant to forget yourself for a moment,
如果能暂时忘掉一切, 那将是一件非常惬意的事
Even if you know it's only an illusion.
即使你知道这只是幻想
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
Oh, yes.
哦, 是的
I was just thinking.
我只是在思考
Do you love life, Doctor?
你热爱生活吗, 医生？
Yes.
是的
There are ups and downs.
有起有落
My family never really had much, but my parents always wanted the best for me,
我的家庭并不富裕, 但我的父母总是想给我最好的
so I was able to go to college and make the most of my life for now.
因此, 我才能上大学, 过上一个在目前看来还不错的生活
You found love?
你找到爱了？
Yes.
是的
I have a little boy.
我有一个小儿子
He's 9 months old.
九个月了
I'm happy for you.
我为你感到高兴
Married?
结婚了？
Divorced.
离了
Life's not a long, quiet river, huh?
生活不是一条风平浪静的长河, 不是吗？
Yep.
是的
Well, now that I've answered your questions, perhaps you'll answer mine.
既然我回答了你这么多问题, 也许你也会回答我的问题吧
Oh, yes, sorry.
哦, 是, 对不起
What was your question?
你的问题是什么？
Just your name.
就你的名字
Doc, short for Douglas.
道克, 道格拉斯的简称
Nobody's called me that for a long time now.
已经很久没人这么叫我了
Do you have any children, Douglas?
你有孩子吗 道格拉斯
Hundreds.
几百个
You're referring to your dogs?
你指的是你的狗？
Yes.
是的
They're my babies.
他们是我的宝贝
Their love saved me a thousand times.
他们的爱千百次地拯救了我
I owe them my life.
我欠他们一条命
Would you say that you love your dogs more than you love human beings?
你认为你爱狗胜过爱人类吗？
Absolutely.
当然
The more I got to know humans, the more I love dogs.
越是了解人类, 我就越是喜欢狗
What qualities do they possess that humans don't have?
它们有哪些特质是人类不具备的吗？
Dogs have beauty without vanity, force without insolence, bravery without ferocity,
狗 有美貌而不虚荣, 有力量而不放肆, 有勇气而不凶残,
and all the virtues humans have without any of the vices.
拥有人类所有的美德, 却没有任何人类的恶习
As far as I can tell, they only have one flaw.
据我所知, 它们只有一个缺陷
Which is?
是？
They trust humans.
它们信任人类
I was probably nine when it first occurred to me.
我第一次想到这个问题时, 大概只有九岁
I remember watching my brother from my bedroom window
我记得我从卧室的窗户看见我的哥哥
as he dangled meat in front of my father's dogs.
看着他把肉挂在我父亲的狗面前
And I watched them both starve in the days leading to the fight.
我看着它们俩在比赛前的日子里忍饥挨饿
That's how my dad earned a living, was organizing dog fights.
我父亲就是靠组织斗狗比赛谋生的
Do you think that he loved them in his own way?
你认为他是在以自己的方式爱着它们吗？
No.
不
My father was incapable of love.
我的父亲不懂得爱
He was all violence.
他只懂暴力
How often did I tell you not to feed the dog?
我告诉过你多少次不要喂狗？
How often?
多少次了？
And you?
你呢？
Oh, me?
哦, 我吗？
I tasted his violence like everyone else.
我尝过他的暴力 和其他人一样
Listening to you, I'm struck by how calm you are.
听了你的话, 我被你的冷静所震撼
Did you ever try to defend yourself or complain at least?
你有试过自卫或投诉吗？
Complaints are prayers to the devil.
投诉不过是对魔鬼的祈祷
Do you have any recollections of happy times?
你还记得任何快乐的时光吗？
Yeah, sure.
是的, 当然
When I was little, when my mom was in the kitchen,
我小时候, 我妈妈在厨房里的时候
she used to love records from Europe most often.
她以前最喜欢欧洲的唱片
And she loved to play them while she was cooking.
她喜欢在做饭时播放这些音乐
And then my dad came home.
然后我爸爸回来了
And the show stopped.
演出就此结束
Did you know anyone else?
你还认识其他人吗？
A grandparent?
祖父母？
An aunt or uncle?
姨妈或者叔叔？
Somebody that could show you some attention or affection?
那些能给你一些关心或爱护的人？
Yes.
是的
A child takes affection where he can get it.
孩子都会随遇而安
And one evening, over dinner,
一天晚上, 在吃晚饭时
my brother delightfully told my father on me.
我的哥哥高兴地向父亲告我的状
He puts his food in his pockets to give to the dogs later
他把吃的放到口袋里, 等会儿去喂狗
No.
没有
That's a lie.
你撒谎
I swear.
我发誓
Cross my heart.
向天发誓
Swear to die.
撒谎就死
Now you love dogs, huh?
现在你爱狗 啊？
Yes.
是的
Please.
求你
Not at the table.
别在餐桌上
More than you love your own family?
比你爱自己的家人还多？
I do.
是
Dogs!
爱狗
You piece of shit!
你个垃圾
Then he took my tears as an admittance of guilt.
然后, 他把我的眼泪当成了认罪
And from that day forward, I was no longer welcome in my father's house.
从那天起, 我在父亲的屋里就不再受欢迎了
-Then occasionally... -This is your family now!
-然后偶尔... -现在这就是你的家人了
And your mother?
你母亲呢？
Oh, my mother, she did the only thing she could do.
哦, 我的母亲, 她做了她唯一能做的事
Some things for you.
这些东西给你
You have to bury them.
你必须埋起来
If your father finds them, he'll go crazy.
如果被你父亲发现, 他又要发疯了
I don't remember exactly what she said, just her face was red and wet.
我不记得她具体说了什么, 只记得她的脸又红又湿
And she apologized.
她还道了歉
I love you.
我爱你
Have a sweet.
祝你愉快
She was pregnant?
她怀孕了？
Yeah, seven months.
对, 七个月
I guess she wanted to offer her child a better life than my brother and I's.
我猜她想让她的孩子过上比我和哥哥更好的生活
Did you ever try to run away?
你有没有试过逃跑？
Or where?
逃去哪？
See, on one side of the pen was the back wall of a kind of shack,
看, 狗棚的后面一侧就是另一个棚子的墙壁
piled high of all kinds of stuff.
那棚子里面堆满了各种杂物
And one day, by scratching at the wood,
有一天, 我推了几下木头,
I was able to squeeze my tiny hands through
就能把小手伸进去
and found a stack of magazines that my mom had been hiding for the obvious reason.
发现了一摞我妈妈藏起来的杂志, 因为那个显而易见的原因
A little window through which I could finally see the world.
通过这扇小洞, 我终于看到了这个世界
You see, I got my whole schooling from Modern Woman and the American Magazine.
你看, 我受的全部教育, 都来自《现代女性》和《美国杂志》
Did you ever realize that your situation wasn't normal?
你有没有意识到你这种情况并不是正常的？
Yeah, I did.
是的 我知道
And how long did you stay in that cage?
你在笼子里待了多久？
Hard to tell.
很难说
Did you resent your mother for abandoning you like that?
你怨恨你的母亲这样抛弃你吗？
No.
不
My mother was weak.
我的母亲是个弱者
It was her biggest flaw and greatest stroke of luck.
这是她最大的缺点, 也是最大的幸运
In the wild, the weak are immediately eliminated, devoured by the others.
在野外, 弱者会被立即淘汰, 被其他动物吞食
But with humans, the weak and cowardly always find a way to survive.
但对于人类来说, 懦弱无能者总能找到方法活下去
For a while, at least.
至少能活上一段时间
Because in the end, God always knows his own.
因为归根结底, 人总是要死的
One more, for Mommy?
再来一口, 为了妈妈？
Yeah.
对
You like that, Yummy?
你喜欢这个, 好吃吧？
One more bite.
再来一口
How was work?
工作怎么样？
Heavy.
沉重
So his Dad crawling around the neighborhood today.
今天他爸爸来附近转悠了
He's not supposed to be in rehab?
他不是应该在戒毒所吗？
Yes, he is.
是的
I thought the judge forbid him to come near the house.
我以为法官已经禁止他靠近这房子了
Yes, she did.
是的
He can be violent.
他可能会来硬的
Yes, I know that, Mom.
是的, 我知道, 妈妈
Like your dad.
就像你爸爸一样
I know that, too.
这我也知道
I'm not going anywhere, baby.
我哪儿也不去, 宝贝
You know it's your fault Mom bailing on us.
你知道这都是你的错, 妈妈抛弃了我们
You made Dad so unhappy that she couldn't stand it anymore.
你让爸爸很不开心, 她再也无法忍受了
Being so pig-headed the whole time.
老是那么猪脑子
So misery all around you.
把自己搞这么悲惨
But you're just a lost sheep.
但你只是一只迷途的羔羊
And with God's help,
在上帝的帮助下
Dad will get you back on the right path.
爸爸会让你回到正确的道路上
Pray and repent, young pagan.
祈祷和忏悔吧, 小异教徒
The wages of sin is death, but the gift
罪的工价是死亡, 但神的恩赐
of God is eternal life in Christ our Lord.
是在我们的主基督里获得永生
Got it?
明白了吗？
IN THE NAME OF GOD
以上帝之名
Hi, I'm here to talk to Dogman.
嗨, 我是来找狗神的
This way, young man.
这边请, 年轻人
Don't be afraid.
别害怕
They won't hurt you.
他们不会伤害你
I apologize, but it's near feeding time.
我很抱歉, 但快到喂食时间了
The agitation is quite high.
他们相当兴奋
You look oddly familiar.
你看起来怪面熟的
Have we met?
我们见过面吗？
Yeah, I, uh... I came here a few months ago with my cousin Pablo.
是的, 我, 呃....我几个月前和我表弟巴勃罗一起来过
We, uh, we did all the electrical.
我们, 呃, 我们安装了所有的电器设备
Juan, right?
胡安, 对吗？
Yeah.
是啊
Yes.
是的
Please, take a seat.
请坐
Something to drink?
喝点什么？
Uh, it's okay.
没事的
I'm not really thirsty.
我真的不渴
So what brings you here, Juan?
什么风把你吹来了, 胡安？
It's Martha.
是玛莎
Martha.
玛莎
She very kindly delivers my laundry from time to time.
她非常好心 时不时地帮我送洗衣物
A great woman.
好女人
Yeah.
是啊
Well, she found a little dog in the street,
她在街上发现了一只小狗
-you know, and she thought... -Oh, my gosh.
-你知道, 她想... -天哪
She thought it'd be happier here, you know, with you.
她觉得它和你在一起会更幸福
Really?
真的吗？
What a little marvel.
真是个小奇迹
It's an Australian labradoodle.
这是一只澳大利亚拉布拉多犬
You know, most are imported illegally.
要知道, 大部分都是非法进口的
Many that go unsold get killed by the dealers or tossed out the car window.
很多卖不出去的 都被经销商杀了 或扔到车窗外面去了
That's likely what happened to this little guy.
这个小家伙很可能就是这样
He's injured his back leg.
他的后腿受伤了
Oh, poor thing.
真可怜
Well, don't you worry.
别担心
You fell from heaven to exactly the right place.
你从天上掉下来, 正好来对了地方
I'm gonna call you gorgeous.
我要叫你小美
Yes.
是的
Be sure to thank Martha for me and tell her
一定要替我感谢玛莎, 并告诉她
if there's anything I can do, just ask.
如果有什么我能做的, 尽管开口
Actually, she has a small problem.
其实, 她遇到了个小麻烦
Go ahead.
说吧
Well, there's a gang in town led by a guy.
镇上有个帮派, 头目叫
Goes by Elver Dugo.
叫什么埃尔·维杜戈.
The executioner.
刽子手
He just opened a bar on 3rd Street, is that correct?
他刚在第三街开了一家酒吧, 是吗？
Yeah, yeah.
对 对
Okay, what about him?
好吧, 他怎么了？
In the last few months, he's been squeezing store owners
最近几个月, 他一直在向我们
in our neighborhood for protection money.
附近的店主索要保护费
We pay up like everybody else, but the guy,
我们和其他人一样付了钱, 但那个人
I mean, he's just bumping it up almost every week.
我的意思是, 他几乎每周都在涨价
Now, Martha can't afford it.
现在, 玛莎付不起了
You know, she had to sell some of her personal furniture.
她不得不卖掉一些私人家具
She inherited it from her folks.
那都是她父母留下来的遗物
Tell Martha I'll see what I can do.
告诉玛莎, 我尽力而为
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'll put it in his mouth.
我要把枪塞进他的嘴里
And then I'll shit on him.
然后我就在他身上拉屎
Hello?
喂？
Hello, Mr. Elver Dugo.
你好, 刽子手先生
I'm sorry to have to call you by this name, but it's the only one I have.
很抱歉这样称呼你, 但这是我只知道这一个名字
Who's this?
你是谁？
Don't worry, I'm not with the police department,
别担心, 我不是警察
the feds, or any of your other known enemies.
不是联邦调查局的, 也不是你的任何一个仇家
Under these circumstances, in fact, I'm your only friend.
事实上, 在这种情况下, 我是你唯一的朋友
First of all, for your own good health, I want you to sit still.
首先, 为了你的健康着想, 我希望你坐好了别动
It could be very dangerous for your future,
这对你的未来可能非常危险
assuming you're thinking of starting a family one day.
假如你还想有一天传宗接代的话
What's the matter?
怎么了？
Hello?
喂？
Yes.
在
Ah, do I have your attention now?
啊, 你现在有认真听了吗？
Si.
是
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
Morales.
莫拉莱斯
What's your first name, Mr. Morales?
你姓什么, 莫拉莱斯先生？
Diego.
迪亚戈
Diego?
迪亚戈？
No.
不
Do you like children, Diego?
你喜欢孩子吗, 迪亚戈？
Yes.
是的
You realize you need them? My dog has its fangs on the half of them, yes.
你知道你需要这命根子 我的狗尖嘴獠牙咬着呢 对吧
Yes.
是的
Here's the deal.
做个交易
I let you have children, and in return, you leave the delightful Martha alone
我给你机会生儿育女, 作为回报, 你们放过亲爱的玛莎
so she too can raise her children in peace and happiness.
这样她也能安宁幸福地抚养孩子
Who the fuck is Martha?
他妈谁是玛莎？
She's an old lady who runs the laundry on the corner of Sixth Street.
她是那个在第六街街角经营洗衣店的老太太
Try taking her your dirty clothes and not your dirty tricks.
试试把你的脏衣服拿给她 而不是你的肮脏小把戏
She'll do a fabulous job on them.
她会洗得非常干净的
How do you like my deal?
你觉得怎么样？
I don't get what the fuck you're saying.
我不明白你在说什么
I'll sum it up for you.
我来给你总结一下
Quit extorting the hell out of her
别再敲诈她了,
or my dog gobbles your gonads right this second.
否则我的狗马上就会咬掉你的生殖器
Got it now?
现在明白了吗？
Yes.
是的
We have a deal?
我们成交了吗？
We have a fucking deal.
妈的成交了
You realize that breaking a deal would be in complete contradiction
你意识到, 破坏协议将会完全
with your values and mine, Mr. Morales, yes?
违背你我的价值观的, 莫拉莱斯先生, 对吗？
I see.
我明白了
Wonderful.
太棒了
Now give the phone back to Mickey, please.
现在请把电话还给米基
Don’t just stand there!
不要傻站在那里！
Bring him back alive!
把他活着抓回来
Come on, come on.
来吧, 来吧
♪ Speak softly, laugh and hold me warm against your heart ♪
♪ 轻声细语, 欢声笑语, 用你的心温暖我 ♪
♪ I feel your words, the tender trembling moments dark ♪
♪ 你温柔的言语, 伴我度过在黑暗中颤抖的时刻 ♪
♪ We're in a world of our own ♪
♪ 我们在自己的世界里 ♪
♪ Sharing a love that only few have ever known ♪
♪ 分享鲜为人知的爱 ♪
♪ Wine-colored days warm like the sun ♪
♪ 葡萄酒般的白昼如阳光般温暖 ♪
♪ The velvet night when we are one ♪
♪ 天鹅绒般的夜晚 我们融为一体 ♪
♪ Speak softly, love, so no one hears us but the sky ♪
♪ 轻轻地告诉我 爱人 除了天空没有人能听到 ♪
♪ The vows of love we made, we'll live until we die ♪
♪ 许下了爱的诺言, 我们至死不渝 ♪
♪ My life is yours, and all because ♪
♪ 我的生命属于你, 一切都是因为 ♪
♪ You came into my world with love, so softly love ♪
♪ 你带着爱进入了我的世界 如此温柔的爱 ♪
♪ So softly love... ♪
♪ 如此温柔的爱 ♪
Melvin, it's not me who's stopping you from seeing your son
梅尔文, 不是我不让你见你儿子
It's the judge, and you know you're not supposed to come near the house.
是法官决定的, 你知道你不应该靠近我家
Look, can you stop, please?
听着, 你能别这样吗？
You're scaring my mom.
你吓到我妈妈了
No, I'm not bringing him to the park.
不, 我不会带他去公园的
It's not good for me and it's not good for him.
对我不好 对他也不好
The best thing for you to do is take care of yourself, okay?
你最应该做的就是照顾好自己, 好吗？
Hello?
喂？
Melvin.
梅尔文
Hello?
喂？
Fuck.
妈的
Excuse me, no parking, ma'am.
对不起, 不能停车, 女士
All right, officer, go ahead.
好的, 警官, 请说
Ma'am?
女士？
God.
上帝啊
Did you hear that from... Ma'am?
你听到...女士？
Did you hear back from them yet?
你收到他们的回复了吗？
-Thank you. -You are welcome...
-谢谢 -不客气
I was allowed to go to your house to bring you some things, as you asked.
他们允许我去你家 给你拿些你要的东西
Thank you.
谢谢
It was pretty messy at your place.
你那里挺乱的
Yes, I'm usually very tidy.
是的, 我通常都很整洁的
You need some help?
需要帮忙吗？
No, Okay, Thank you
不用 没事 谢谢
Caramel latte with whipped cream, right?
焦糖拿铁加生奶油, 对吗？
Perfect, thank you.
太好了, 谢谢
No, I shouldn't. Sugar's bad for me.
不 我不该喝这个 糖对我不好
Cutting out all of life's little pleasures is even worse, don't you think?
摒弃生活中所有的小甜蜜, 只会更糟糕, 你觉得呢？
Must be exhausted.
一定累坏了
You only got a few hours sleep.
你只睡了几个小时
A good coffee and I'm ready for anything.
喝上一杯好咖啡, 我就能满血复活
Anyway, your story is very fascinating,
无论如何, 你的故事非常吸引人,
and I still have no news on when and where they're gonna transfer you,
我仍然不知道他们什么时候会转移你去哪里
so I would love to ask you a few more questions about your childhood,
我想再问几个关于你童年的问题
if you don't mind.
如果你不介意的话
Well, it's a bit late for that, don't you think?
现在说这个有点晚了, 你不觉得吗？
Meaning?
什么意思？
To train an animal well, the earlier you start, the better.
要想训练好动物, 越早开始越好
I'm too old to be retrained, don't you think?
我太老了, 重训也训不好了, 你觉得呢？
Do you find talking about your childhood awkward or uncomfortable?
你是否觉得谈论自己的童年很尴尬或不自在？
No.
不会
I'm just not used to it.
我只是不习惯
Actually, it feels like it probably does me some good.
事实上, 我觉得这可能对我有好处
No one exists without a past, right?
每个人都有过去, 对吧？
Well, they say the past is the root that becomes the tree.
他们说, 过去是根, 是成材之本
True, but roots are invisible. Why dig them up?
没错 但根是看不见的 为什么要挖出来呢？
Because it does you good.
因为这对你有好处
Touche.
不错
So what do you want to know?
你想知道什么？
How did you get out of that cage?
你是怎么逃出那个笼子的？
I see them!
我看到他们了
Look at this.
看看这个
No, Richie
不要 里奇
Wait and see what Dad's gonna do to your puppies when he finds out.
等着看爸爸发现后会怎么处置你的小狗吧
He'll make dog food out of them.
他会拿它们来做狗食
Richie, please.
里奇, 求你了
-Don't do that. -Or else?
-别这么做 -否则呢？
Don't do that, Richie.
别这样, 里奇
Richie, please.
里奇, 求你了
My brother, Richie, betrayed me once again,
我的哥哥里奇又一次背叛了我
went into the house and told my father.
走进屋子, 告诉了我父亲
My father was a sick man.
我父亲有病
He hated the world, starting with himself.
他憎恨这个世界, 憎恨他自己
He didn't love life.
他并不热爱生命
He tried to constantly destroy it.
他不断试图摧毁它
-Move. -No, no. No, please. Please.
-走开 -不 不 别这样 求你了
I have enough.
我受够了
I said move.
我说了走开
Move, or I'll get you.
走开, 不然我抓到你
-I'll feed them -Get the hell out of the way!
-我来喂它们 -给我让开
Move away!
走开
They came out with a shotgun to prove some kind of point
他们拿着猎枪出来 想证明些什么
and I wouldn't get out of the way, the gun went off and I lost a finger.
我不愿意闪开, 结果枪走火了, 我失去了一根手指
Hey, hey, hey!
嘿, 嘿, 嘿！
Dad, Dad, Dad!
爸爸 爸爸
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
没事, 没事, 没事
No, stop, stop.
不, 停下, 停下
I got this, I got this, I got this.
我来, 我来
Let's go inside, let's go inside.
我们进去吧, 我们进去吧
You didn't do anything, it's not your fault, okay?
你什么都没做, 这不是你的错, 好吗？
Come on, come on.
来吧, 来吧
No, Dad, Dad, Dad, listen to me.
不 爸爸 爸爸 听我说
Go inside, come on, come on.
进去, 快点, 快点
It's okay, I got this.
没关系, 我来搞定
It's not your fault, go inside.
这不是你的错, 进去吧
Come on, come on.
来吧, 来吧
Go, I got this, okay?
去吧, 我来处理, 好吗？
You see?
看到了吗？
You refuse to understand.
你拒绝理解
You refuse to accept the error of your ways, and you behave like an animal!
你拒绝接受自己的错误, 你就像个畜牲！
You do not deserve God's love, only his mercy.
你不配得到上帝的爱, 只配得到他的怜悯
In nomine Patris et Filii et Spiritus Sancti.
奉圣父圣子圣灵的名求
Amen.
阿门
Moby, you see this?
莫比, 你看到了吗？
Car.
汽车
I want you to find them and give them this.
我要你找到他们, 把这个交给他们
The police car.
警车
You got that?
明白了吗？
The car in the back.
后面那个车
Go, Moby.
去吧, 莫比
Whoa, You cheeky what.
哇, 你这厚脸皮的家伙
What's up, little fella?
怎么了, 小家伙？
He looks like he's trying to tell us something.
它好像想告诉我们什么
Is it one of your informers?
它是你们的线人吗？
Very funny.
非常有趣
I'm going straight up to the second floor.
我会直接上二楼
You cover me on the stairs, all right?
你在楼梯上掩护我, 好吗？
Let's go. Come on.
我们走 来吧
Go upstairs.
上楼
Let's go.
我们走吧
Jesus.
天啊
We're gonna need backup.
我们需要后援
Ambulance and social services.
呼叫救护车和社会服务
Come on, let's go.
来吧, 我们走
It's done. Don't move.
好了 别动
Hands off the gun now!
把枪拿开
Get the police!
报警
Put your hands on your head! Put your hands on your head, right now!
双手抱头 双手抱头 立刻
That might have been the best day of my life if by unfortunate coincidence
这可能是我一生中最美好的一天, 如果没有不幸的巧合的话
the bullet hadn't ricocheted off the wall and launched itself into my spinal cord.
子弹从墙上弹出, 射进了我的脊柱
I was free at last, but God had deprived me of legs to enjoy my freedom.
我终于自由了, 但上帝却剥夺了我享受自由的双腿
I do believe in God,
我是相信上帝
But I think at that point in my life,
但我认为, 在我人生的那个阶段
the question I asked myself was, did God believe in me?
我问了自己一个问题就是, 上帝相信我吗？
I see you are fitted with a system of leg braces.
我看到你安装了一套腿部支撑系统
Can you walk?
你能走路吗？
A bit.
一点点
They allow me to take steps in emergencies.
它们能让我在紧急情况下走几步
But the bullet was in a very delicate position.
但那颗子弹处在一个非常微妙的位置
And right or wrong, the doctors didn't want to risk taking it out.
无论对错, 医生们都不想冒险把它取出来
So with every step I take, there's a chance of my bone marrow
因此, 我每走一步, 都有可能将骨髓
emptying out to the body, which is not highly recommended.
排出体外, 所以这是非常不建议的
I can walk, but only to my death.
我能走, 但只能走向死亡
Very Shakespearean, don't you think?
很有莎士比亚的风格, 你觉得呢？
And your father and your brother, how long did they get?
你的父亲和哥哥, 他们被判了多久？
Father got 20.
父亲判了20年
Killed himself two weeks after his arrest.
被捕两周后自杀身亡了
I guess he didn't have my capacity for cage life.
我猜他没有我在铁笼中生存的能力
And your brother?
你哥哥呢？
My brother got 12.
我哥哥判了12年
Thanks to God and good behavior, he only served eight.
感谢上帝和良好表现, 他只坐了八年牢
Did you ever see him again?
你后来见过他吗？
Yes, I did.
是的, 见过
The day he was released.
他被释放的那天
These papers?
这些文件？
Get out of here.
离开这里
They let him out in the morning,
他们早上把他放出来的
and one of my more diligent dogs, Paulie, was there waiting for him.
我的一条很勤快的狗 保利 也在那里等着他
♪ Rumors spreadin' round ♪
♪ 谣言四起 ♪
♪ And I had to take the time ♪
♪ 我不得不花时间 ♪
♪ To find a shack outside the game ♪
♪ 找一个庇护之所 ♪
♪ You know what I'm talkin' about. ♪
♪ 你知道我在说什么啊 ♪
♪ Just let me know if you wanna go ♪
♪ 告诉我哦 如果你想走 ♪
♪ To that whole mile on the range ♪
♪ 去那一望无际的牧场 ♪
♪ They got a lot of nice girls out here. ♪
♪ 那里有很多漂亮姑娘 ♪
Your dogs killed your brother.
你的狗咬死了你哥哥
No.
不
God, in his great wisdom, put him out of his misery.
上帝 以其伟大的智慧 让他脱离了苦海
Excuse me, ma'am.
对不起, 女士
Thank you.
谢谢
Mind if I have a bite to eat?
介意我吃点东西吗？
Please do.
你随意
It's not exactly good, but my appetite's back.
虽然不是很好吃, 但我的胃口又回来了
I don't know, maybe it has something to do with your presence.
我不知道, 也许和你在边上有关
That's good.
很好
But as a matter of procedure, I must tell you
但按照程序, 我必须告知你
that our conversations are being recorded.
我们的谈话会被录音
There's a camera on the ceiling.
天花板上有个摄像头
Two, actually.
两个 实际上
I know.
我知道
You want one?
你要来一个吗？
No, thank you.
不用了, 谢谢
I see here that, uh, after you were discharged from the hospital,
在这上面我看到 你出院以后
You were sent to a care home, the first of several I see.
被送进了一个庇护所, 我看到这里有好几家
Do you have any recollection of that time?
你还记得当时的情景吗？
I swapped out one prison for another, more spacious and comfortable,
我从一个监狱换到了另一个更宽敞舒适的监狱
sure, but without my dogs, my isolation was even greater.
当然, 没有我的狗, 我的孤独感只会更强烈
You didn't make any friends?
你没有交到朋友吗？
No.
不
Dogs have a real sense of family.
狗有一种真正的家庭感
Even when they come from different breeds,
即使是不同的品种
they rally around in the bad times and form a solid, united entity.
他们也会在逆境中团结一致, 形成一个坚实团结的整体
The kids I met in the homes were already scarred
我在庇护所遇到的孩子们已经伤痕累累
and beaten by life, incapable of uniting.
被生活打倒, 团结不起来了
They only listened to their survival instincts.
他们只听从生存的本能
When you see dogs love their friends and bite their enemies,
你看狗 他们敌我分明
quite unlike people, you always have to mix love and hate.
而人完全不同, 他们的爱和恨总是纠缠不清
You ever have any romantic relationships?
你谈过恋爱吗？
That's not true.
事实并非如此
There was one, actually.
还真有一个
Selma.
塞尔玛
Hello.
你好
Douglas, right?
道格拉斯, 对吧？
I'm Selma.
我是塞尔玛
The librarian tells me you're a great reader.
图书管理员告诉我, 你很爱看书
Have you read this before?
你以前读过这本书吗？
Do you know Shakespeare?
你知道莎士比亚吗？
Oh, my God, I'm about to change your world.
哦, 天哪, 那我要颠覆你的世界了
Shakespeare is the greatest writer of all time.
莎士比亚是有史以来最伟大的作家
You can imagine, all these playwrights are inspired
你可以想象, 所有这些剧作家都受过
by this man that
wrote plays 400 years ago.
And the best one, in my opinion, is Macbeth.
而在我看来, 最好的一部是《麦克白》
She was a counselor, taught a drama class.
她是辅导员, 教戏剧课
As beautiful as the sunbeams,
像阳光一样美丽,
she could talk about Shakespeare like nobody.
她谈起莎士比亚来如数家珍
She taught me how to put on makeup.
她教我如何化妆
She said that if you didn't like your reflection, you just had to change it.
她说, 如果你不喜欢你在镜子里的样子, 你只需要改变它
You know, nothing proves that the reflection
要知道, 谁也没有证明镜子里反射出来的
in the mirror is fake and we are real.
我们是假的以及我们是真的
Maybe the reflection is convinced that it is reality and we simply copy.
也许镜子里的我们才是现实, 而我们才是复制品
I've never met anyone like her.
我从没见过像她这样的人
Okay, your turn.
好了 轮到你了
Moustache.
小胡子
I can't.
我做不到
Of course you can.
你当然可以
You can do anything you want.
你可以做任何你想做的事
You can be a king or a prince.
你可以是国王, 也可以是王子
You can be a beggar or a flower.
你可以是乞丐, 也可以是鲜花
Anything you choose.
任君选择
Okay, okay.
好吧 好吧
She said the theater was like a religion,
她说, 剧院就像一种宗教
a propo position that the true believer experiences as reality.
是个可以让真正的信徒将那里的体验视为现实的一个好地方
And remember, if you can play Shakespeare, you can play anything.
记住, 如果你能演莎士比亚, 你就能演任何角色
♪ as in truth I speak to you as if from some high hill. ♪
♪ 就像我从高山上对你们说话一样 ♪
♪ True, and you kill me from that high part, ♪
♪ 没错, 你从高处杀了我 ♪
♪ that one harsh word fall upon my heart. ♪
♪ 那一句刺耳的话落在了我的心上 ♪
♪ My ears have not yet drunk a hundred words of my tongue's utterings yet. ♪
♪ 我的耳朵还没有听过我的舌头说出的一百句话 ♪
♪ I know the sound. ♪
♪ 我知道那声音 ♪
♪ Art thou not Romeo and Montague? ♪
♪ 你不是罗密欧与蒙太古吗？ ♪
♪ Neither, fair saint, if either thee dislike. ♪
♪ 圣人, 如果你不喜欢, 我也不喜欢 ♪
♪ My dearest love, Duncan comes here tonight. ♪
♪ 我最亲爱的爱人 邓肯今晚会来这里 ♪
♪ And when goes hence? ♪
♪ 什么时候离开？ ♪
♪ Tomorrow, as he purposes. ♪
♪ 明天, 他计划好的 ♪
♪ Oh, never shall some admirer see. ♪
♪ 哦, 再也不会有仰慕者看到了 ♪
♪ Now, mother, what's the matter? ♪
♪ 现在 母后 怎么了？ ♪
♪ Hamlet, you have offended your father. ♪
♪ 哈姆雷特 你冒犯了你的父王 ♪
♪ Mother, you have offended my father. ♪
♪ 母后, 你冒犯了我的父王 ♪
♪ You may indeed say so, for it was that hand that gave away my heart. ♪
♪ 你确实可以这么说, 因为正是那只手把我的心交给了他 ♪
♪ A liberal hand. ♪
♪ 自由之手 ♪
♪ The hearts of all gave hands. ♪
♪ 所有人都伸出了双手 ♪
♪ But I know heraldry is hands, not hearts. ♪
♪ 但我知道纹章是手, 不是心 ♪
♪ My name, dear saint, is hateful to myself because it is an enemy to thee. ♪
♪ 亲爱的圣人, 我恨死了我的名字, 因为那是你的敌人之名 ♪
♪ Had I written, I would tear the word. ♪
♪ 如果是我写, 我会撕掉这个词 ♪
♪ Ramia. ♪
♪ 拉米亚 ♪
♪ Let all those who love me, follow me! ♪
♪ 让所有爱我的人 跟随我！ ♪
When I was alive at last, I could fully express myself, my whole body.
我终于活了过来, 我可以充分表达我自己, 全心全意的
I was what I wanted to be, and the barriers of
我想成为谁就成为谁, 现实的阻碍
reality were dismantled by makeup and verse.
被化妆和诗句所瓦解
You see, while the real world constantly rejected me,
你看, 当现实世界不断拒绝我的时候
the imaginary one opened its arms and welcomed me fully.
想象中的世界张开双臂, 欢迎我的到来
And in this new kingdom, Selma was my princess.
在这个新王国里, 塞尔玛是我的公主
You loved her?
你爱她？
Madly.
疯狂地
Did you tell her?
你告诉她了吗？
I was getting ready to, but one day she left.
我正准备这样做, 但有一天她离开了
The theater group in Boston suburbs had hired her.
波士顿郊区的剧团聘用了她
I was happy for her.
我为她感到高兴
Her talent deserved far better than a home for juvenile delinquents.
她的才华应该得到比少年犯之家更好的待遇
That's for sure.
这是肯定的
Did you lose track of her?
你找不到她了吗？
I followed her every step.
我追踪着她的每一步
She struggled to begin with.
她的起步比较困难
But Selma had too much talent and love to not to succeed.
但是, 塞尔玛有那么多天赋和爱, 不可能不成功
Very soon, she started working with more professional outfits,
很快, 她开始穿上了更专业的戏服
and within a few years, she worked her way up to Broadway.
没过几年, 她就登上了百老汇舞台
And eventually, I was able to get the courage to go and see her.
最终, 我鼓起勇气去见了她
She was beautiful.
她很漂亮
And I asked one of the security guards
我问一名保安
if I could go backstage, and he let me come.
我是否可以去后台, 他就让我进去了
Come in.
请进
Sorry to bother you, Selma.
抱歉打扰你, 塞尔玛
There's someone here. Says he's your number one fan.
这里有个人 说他是你的头号粉丝
He knows you, and can he say hi?
他认识你, 能跟你打个招呼吗？
Sure.
当然
I was absolutely terrified that she wouldn't remember me.
我非常害怕她不记得我了
But she did. Instantly.
但她记起来了 立刻
Oh, my gosh.
哦, 我的天哪
Douglas!
道格拉斯
Oh, mon Dieu.
哦 上帝啊
Look how you've grown!
看看你都长多大了
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吗？
Look at this outfit!
看看这身打扮
Decked out like a prince!
打扮得像个王子
I wanted to throw these to you at the end, but I was scared for my position.
本想结束的时候把这花扔给你的, 但我担心我的位置
They wouldn't hit the stage.
扔不到台上
They're beautiful.
好漂亮
Come on, let's go get them in a vase.
来吧, 我去插在花瓶里
This is amazing.
太神奇了
I was only thinking about you the other day, wondering what happened to you.
我前几天才想起你, 想知道你怎么样了
I'm warning you, I want the full story.
我警告你, 我要知道全部事情
Shoot.
说吧
Okay.
好的
Well, I kept reading.
好吧, 我继续读书
That could be what I do best.
这可能是我最擅长的
Then I passed a number of exams.
然后我通过了一些考试
I did a college course.
我上过大学课程
Ah, fantastico.
啊, 太棒了
You must have made friends there.
你一定在那里交到了朋友
No, it was an online course.
不, 这是一门在线课程
The campus was too far from the home I was in.
校园离我住的那一家太远了
I only went once a month for exams and stuff,
我每个月只去一次, 参加考试什么的
but it didn't stop me from getting my B.S.C. in biology.
但这并不妨碍我获得生物学学士学位
A B.S.C.? That's really good.
一个学士学位？真不错
What was your dissertation about?
你的论文是关于什么的？
Dogs.
狗
I should have guessed. You were always talking about them back then.
我早该想到的 那时候你就总是谈论它们
Look, they're beautiful.
看, 多漂亮
Not as beautiful as you.
没你漂亮
So sweet.
真贴心
And acting, you kept up with it?
表演呢 你还在坚持？
A bit.
有点
It's not really the same without you, though.
不过, 没有你, 一切都不一样了
I hope so.
但愿如此
But I followed your career from the beginning.
但我从一开始就在关注你的职业生涯
Really?
真的吗？
Look, I cut out every article I could find
看, 我剪下了所有能找到的文章
since your very first production in Boston.
从你在波士顿的第一部作品开始
You did this?
这是你做的？
For you.
给你的
You like it?
喜欢吗？
This is the most beautiful gift anyone has given me in a long time.
这是长久以来别人送给我的最漂亮的礼物
And she seemed genuinely happy that I was there.
她似乎真的很高兴我在那里
And then...
然后
Come in.
请进
What a show.
真是一场好戏
Ah, thank you.
啊, 谢谢你
They loved it.
他们很喜欢
Thank you.
谢谢
Douglas, this is Bradley, my director,
道格拉斯, 这位是布拉德利, 我的导演,
who also happens to be my husband.
同时也是我的丈夫
Hey, Doug.
嘿, 道格
I heard a lot about you, man.
我听说了很多关于你的事
Cool.
酷毙了
He's also the future daddy of my baby.
他还是我孩子未来的爸爸
Douglas.
道格拉斯
Congratulations.
祝贺你
How long have you been...
你们多久了...
Two weeks.
两周
Really? That's fast.
真的吗？ 真快
You're already pregnant.
你已经怀孕了
You mean Bradley?
你是说布拉德利？
No, we met three years ago and took our time getting
不, 我们三年前相识的, 慢慢地走到了一起
to know each other and got married last winter.
去年冬天结的婚
And the baby really is new.
宝宝真的是刚有的
You're one of the first to know.
你是最先知道的人
I haven't even told my family yet.
我都还没有告诉我的家人呢
I'm... I'm flattered. That is...
我...我受宠若惊...
It's cool.
酷
Look, babe, Douglas made this for me.
宝贝, 这是道格拉斯为我做的
Really?
真的吗？
He kept every article about me since I started out.
他保留了我出道以来关于我的每一篇文章
Wow.
哇
Isn't it adorable?
是不是很可爱？
It's beautiful.
太美了
That's true artistry, man.
真正的艺术, 伙计
Wow, wow, wow.
哇, 哇, 哇
So you're a member of the clan, right?
你也是做这行的, 对吧？
You're in the artistic family?
你是搞艺术的？
You're in the show business?
你也是演艺界的？
No.
不
I'm in the dog business.
我是做狗生意的
So that evening, I went back to the shelter
于是那天晚上, 我回到了那个
where I'd been working for the past five years.
工作了五年的庇护所
I felt so, so stupid.
我觉得自己非常非常愚蠢
And she was older, gorgeous, and successful.
她更成熟 更漂亮 更成功
I was just this guy in a wheelchair
我只是一个坐在轮椅上的
who, even if he could walk, I would have no idea where to go.
就算能走路也不知道该往哪里走的残废
How could I think for one second that she felt anything but pity for me?
我怎么能认为 她对我除了怜悯之外 还会有其他感情呢？
No!
不
Their love for me was so genuine, true, pure, without any trickery or pretense.
他们对我的爱是如此真挚 真实 纯洁, 没有任何欺骗或伪装
Dogs never lie when they talk about love.
狗在谈到爱时从不说谎
What happened next?
后来呢？
I adapt.
我适应了
Again.
再一次
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
对不起, 我不明白
You want to shut down the shelter?
你们想关闭动物庇护所？
The state is running a huge deficit
国家正面临巨额赤字
and the new governor has launched a drastic cost-cutting program.
而新州长已经启动了一项大幅削减成本的计划
Funding to your organization has been stopped.
对贵组织的资助已被停止
The funding I receive has been cut in half every year for the last three years,
在过去的三年里, 我获得的资助每年都被削减一半,
but thanks to donations and regularly placing dogs, we cost the state next to nothing.
但得益于捐赠和定期安置狗只, 我们几乎没有花费州里一分钱
You have done remarkable work.
你的工作非常出色
We fully understand that, but we have received
我们完全理解这一点, 但我们收到了
numerous complaints for various kinds of nuisance.
许多关于各种滋扰的投诉
Oh, nuisance such as?
哦, 比如说？
Such as odors.
例如气味
City Hall have decided to sell the land to a developer.
市政厅已决定将这块土地出售给开发商
Oh, so it's all about money.
哦, 原来都是为了钱
We're just carrying out orders, you know?
我们只是执行命令, 你知道吗？
Yes, I know.
是的, 我知道
And what happens to the dogs?
这些狗怎么办？
We release them and ask them kindly to go back to their families?
放了他们, 然后请他们乖乖回老家去？
I guess they'll be taken to a more suitable facility.
我猜它们会被送到一个更合适的地方
I know what that's like.
我知道那种感觉
Going from home to home and never getting a shot at rebuilding your life.
从一个家换到另一个家, 永远没有机会重建自己的生活
Your record here is beyond reproach.
你在这里的记录无可指责
I am sure social services will soon find you another position.
我相信社会服务部门很快就会为你找到另一个职位
So when's the big day?
所以是哪一天？
In theory, Monday morning, 6 a.m.
理论上, 星期一早上 6 点
We can ask them for more time if you like.
如果你愿意, 我们可以要求更多一点时间
Get you an extension.
给你延个期
No, thank you, though.
不用, 还是得谢谢你, 不过
I'll see you on Monday.
周一见
Okay, uh, Monday.
好吧, 呃, 星期一
-Good morning, sir. -Good morning.
-早上好, 先生 -早上好
Firstly, we bring out the manager.
首先, 我们把经理请出来
The guy's in a wheelchair.
那家伙坐着轮椅
It's a bit of an oddball.
有点古怪
And we take care of the dogs.
我们来处理狗
Understood.
明白了
新泽西州犬只庇护所新泽西动物管制部
What the fuck?
搞什么鬼？
We'll be okay here.
我们在这里会没事的
Polly, tell the others, okay?
波莉, 通知大家, 好吗？
I take thee at thy word:
我相信你的话
Call me but love, and I'll be new baptized
叫我亲爱的, 我就会接受新的洗礼
Henceforth I never will be Romeo.
从此我不再是罗密欧
What man art thou that thus bescreen'd in night, so stumblest on my counsel?
你是何方神圣, 竟在黑夜中窥探我的心思？
By a name I know not how to tell thee who I am.
我不知道如何用名字告诉你我是谁
What's in a name that which we call a rose?
我们称之为玫瑰的名字里有什么？
by any other word would smell as sweet.
就算用别的词来命名 一样还是那么甜蜜
So Romeo would, were he not Romeo called,
罗密欧也是如此, 如果他不叫罗密欧
retain that dear perfection which he owes without that title.
保留他的完美 没有这个称号
Romeo, doff thy name, and for thy name,
罗密欧 放弃你的名字 为了那个
which is no part of thee, take all myself.
不属于你的名字 带走我的一切
I take thee at thy word.
我相信你的话
Call me but love, and I'll be new baptized.
叫我亲爱的, 我就会接受新的洗礼
Henceforth, I never will be Romeo.
从此我不再是罗密欧
Did you ever see Selma again?
你后来还见过塞尔玛吗？
No.
没有
She had two children in quick succession.
她接连生了两个孩子
She quit acting.
她放弃了表演
Her husband turned to beer.
她的丈夫爱上了啤酒
Even the stars fade and go out in the end.
即使是耀眼的星星, 最终也会褪色熄灭
The place where you were living, it was pretty well-equipped.
你住的地方设备很齐全
How did you do that?
你是怎么做到的？
I help people. People help me back.
我帮助别人 别人也会回报我
Yes, but it must have cost a lot of money, right?
是的, 但一定花了很多钱, 对吗？
True.
没错
To begin with, it was difficult.
起初, 困难重重
I had to pick up a job.
我不得不去找个工作
But I had trouble finding one.
但我很难找到
My biology degree couldn't even
我的生物学学位甚至不能
open the doors to a fast food restaurant.
敲开快餐店的大门
Oh, but you don't smell the flowers, do you?
哦, 但你不能闻花香, 对吧？
It's my flowers. I pay for them.
这是我的花 我花钱买的
♪ Sweet dreams are made of this. ♪
♪ 美梦由此铸就 ♪
♪ Who am I to disagree? ♪
♪ 我有什么资格反对？ ♪
♪ I travel the world and the seven seas. ♪
♪ 我周游世界和七大洋 ♪
Sorry, we don't have anything right now.
对不起, 我们现在没有任何职位
♪ Everybody is looking for something. ♪
♪ 每个人都在寻找什么 ♪
♪ Some of them want to use you ♪
♪ 有些人想要利用你 ♪
♪ Some of them want to get used by you ♪
♪ 而有些人则想要被你利用 ♪
Sorry.
对不起
♪ Some of them want to abuse you ♪
♪ 有些人想要诬蔑于你 ♪
♪ Some of them want to be abused ♪
♪ 而有些人却想要被你诬蔑 ♪
Sorry.
对不起
♪ Sweet dreams are made of this. ♪
♪ 美梦由此铸就 ♪
♪ Who am I to disagree? ♪
♪ 我有什么资格反对？ ♪
♪ I travel the world and the seven seas. ♪
♪ 我周游世界和七大洋 ♪
♪ Everybody's looking for something. ♪
♪ 每个人都在寻找什么 ♪
♪ Sweet dreams are made of this. ♪
♪ 美梦由此铸就 ♪
♪ Who am I to disagree? ♪
♪ 我有什么资格反对？ ♪
♪ I travel the world and the seven seas. ♪
♪ 我周游世界和七大洋 ♪
♪ Everybody's looking for something. ♪
♪ 每个人都在寻找什么 ♪
Good job, bro.
干得漂亮 兄弟
Beautiful, Annie. Beautiful.
漂亮 安妮 漂亮
Thank you, Annie.
谢谢你, 安妮
Cher, you were on just after this number and before the magician.
雪儿 你在这个号码之后 魔术师之前上场
This is doing my favor.
就当帮我个忙.
Um... Rodney?
嗯....罗德尼？
Yes?
什么事？
I came about the ad at the door.
我在门口看到广告
Sorry, I'm...
对不起, 我...
Oh, the bar job. We found someone.
哦 酒吧的活 我们找到人了
I'm sorry. I forgot to take the ad off the door.
对不起 我忘了把门上的广告撕掉
I'm sorry. Have a good day.
对不起 祝你愉快
Actually, I was thinking maybe another job.
事实上, 我想看看另一份工作
I'm an artist, too, you see.
你看, 我也是个艺术家
You mean, like, do an act?
你是说 表演吗？
I know all of Shakespeare by heart.
莎士比亚的作品我都滚瓜烂熟
Kid, you're in the wrong theater. This is a drag show.
孩子 你走错剧院了 这是变装秀
No, I understand, but I'm...
不, 我明白, 但我...
If you can perform Shakespeare, you can perform anything.
如果你可以表演莎士比亚, 你就可以表演任何东西
I also know a whole repertoire of old songs, so I have that to offer as well.
我还会唱好几首老歌, 所以我也能干好这个
I'm sure you can perform, but get this.
我相信你会表演, 但你要明白这一点
Folks come here to have fun, not to
人们来这里是为了找乐子, 而不是
watch some cross-dresser in a wheelchair.
来看一些坐在轮椅上的异装癖的
I can stand.
我能站起来
For one song.
就一首歌
Rodney, come on.
罗德尼, 别这样
Give him a chance.
给他一个机会
-Just give him a little one. -He stood.
-就给他一个小机会 -他站起来了
-Come on. -Rodney, please.
-拜托 -拜托 罗德尼
Oh, for me.
哦, 为了我
-No, he stood. -Come on. Look at him.
-不 他站着呢 -来吧 看看他
-One night. -Yes. Yes.
-就一个晚上 -好 好
♪ Does he love me? ♪
♪ 他爱我吗？ ♪
♪ I want to know. ♪
♪ 我想知道 ♪
♪ How will I know if he loves me? ♪
♪ 我怎么知道他是否爱我？ ♪
♪ So is it in his eyes? ♪
♪ 那么是在他的眼里吗？ ♪
♪ Oh, no, you'll be deceived. ♪
♪ 哦, 不, 你会被骗的 ♪
♪ Is it in his smile? ♪
♪ 是在他的笑容里吗？ ♪
-The big reveal. - ♪ Oh, no, you'll never believe it. ♪
-大揭秘 - ♪ 哦, 不, 你绝对不会相信 ♪
♪ You want to know... ♪
♪ 你想知道 ♪
Girls, the crowd tonight is a little quiet, so if we
姑娘们, 今晚的人群有点安静, 所以如果我们
could just bring up the energy, that'd be perfect.
如果能多来点能量, 那就再好不过了
Cher?
雪儿？
Could you shut up for a second?
你能闭嘴一会儿吗？
Wow.
哇
Rude.
粗鲁
Douglas, you're on in two minutes.
道格拉斯, 你还有两分钟
You look beautiful.
你看起来真美
Thank you.
谢谢
I thought you couldn't walk without those.
我还以为没有这个你就走不了路呢
I can't.
走不了
But I can stand still... for a moment.
但我可以....站一会儿
-Are you sure about this? -Yeah
-你确定要这样吗 -确定
Just don't leave me over there at the end.
只要结束之后别把我扔在那边
No, of course not.
不, 当然不会
As soon as the song is over.
歌曲一结束
I need you to be there to pick me up.
我需要你来接我
Promise me.
答应我
I promise you I'll be there.
我保证我会去的
Give it up for our fantastic magician.
为我们的神奇魔术师鼓掌
Wasn't he incredible?
他是不是很不可思议？
Unfortunately, though, our magician will be taking a short
但不幸的是, 我们的魔术师要在
sabbatical after the teeniest and tiniest of incidents.
最微不足道的事故之后 短暂休个小假
Just relax.
放轻松
-Next up for you, we have something you've never seen before. -Ready？
-接下来, 我们将带来一些你从未见过的表演 -准备好了？
A completely new kind of...
一种全新的...
Okay.
好了
One, two...
一 二...
Okay.
好了
We'll be right here.
我们就在这里
Okay.
好的
Good luck.
祝你好运
Now, without further ado, let me welcome to the
现在, 话不多说, 让我来欢迎
stage the French diva herself, Miss Edith Piaf!
法国天后伊迪丝·琵雅芙小姐登台！
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
My words as well.
我也是这么说的
♪ Je revois la ville en fête et en délire ♪
♪ 我看到这座城市沉浸在节日的狂欢中 ♪
♪ Suffoquant sous le soleil et sous la joie ♪
♪ 在阳光和欢乐中窒息 ♪
♪ Et j'entends dans la musique les cris et les rires ♪
♪ 我听到音乐中的呼喊声和欢笑声 ♪
♪ Qui éclatent et rebondissent autour de moi ♪
♪ 迸发出来, 四处蹦跳 ♪
♪ Et perdu parmi ces gens qui me pousculent ♪
♪ 我迷失在人群中, 他们把我推来推去 ♪
♪ Et tout dit, désemparé, je reste là ♪
♪ 我心烦意乱地呆在那里 ♪
♪ Quand soudain je me retourne, ils se reculent ♪
♪ 突然我转过身来, 他们退后, ♪
♪ Et la foule vient me jeter entre ses bras ♪
♪ 人群涌来, 把我拥入怀中 ♪
♪ Emportés par la foule qui nous traîne, nous entraîne, écrasés ♪
♪ 被人群拖着走, 拖着走, 压着走 ♪
♪ l'un contre l'autre, nous ne formons qu'un seul corps. ♪
♪ 我们形成一个整体 ♪
♪ Et le flot, sans effort, nous pousse à enchaîner l'un et ♪
♪ 这种流动 不费吹灰之力 就能推动我们一个又一个 ♪
♪ l'autre, et nous laisse tous deux épanouis, enivrés et heureux. ♪
♪ 让我们彼此绽放 陶醉和幸福 ♪
♪ Entraînés par la foule qui s'élance et qui danse ♪
♪ 在人群的簇拥下, 我们向前奔跑, 翩翩起舞 ♪
♪ Une folle par en dehors de nos deux mains reste soudée ♪
♪ 我们的两只手依然紧紧地握在一起 ♪
♪ Et parfois soulevés, nos deux corps enlacés s'envolent ♪
♪ 有时, 我们两个纠缠在一起的身体会飞走, ♪
♪ Et retombent tous deux épanouis en y briser ♪
♪ 然后双双倒下, 绽放, 融入其中 ♪
♪ Et la joie que l'a poussée par son sourire ♪
♪ 她的微笑所带来的喜悦刺痛了我 ♪
♪ Me transperce et rejaillit au fond de mon âme ♪
♪ 涌入我的灵魂深处 ♪
♪ Mais soudain je poussais un cri parmi les rires ♪
♪ 我突然在笑声中放声大哭起来 ♪
♪ Quand la foule vient l'arracher d'entendre mes bras ♪
♪ 当人群把他从我怀里扯走 ♪
♪ Emportée par la foule qui nous traîne, nous entraîne, ♪
♪ 被人群带着走, 拖着我们走 ♪
♪ nous éloigne l'un de l'autre, je lutte et je me débarque. ♪
♪ 我在战斗, 我在躲避 ♪
♪ Mais le son de ma voix s'écouffe dans le rire des autres ♪
♪ 但我的声音消失在他们的笑声中 ♪
♪ et je crie de douleur, de fureur et de rage et je pleure. ♪
♪ 我在痛苦 愤怒和暴躁中呐喊 痛哭 ♪
♪ Entraînée par la foule qui s’élance Et qui danse ♪
♪ 被汹涌的人群带走 ♪
♪ Une folle farandole Je suis emportée au loin ♪
♪ 跳起疯狂的法兰多尔舞, 我被带向远方 ♪
♪ Et je crispe mes poings, maudissant la foule qui me vole ♪
♪ 我握紧拳头, 诅咒从我身边偷走东西的人群 ♪
♪ L'homme qu'elle m'avait donné Et que je n'ai jamais retrouvé… ♪
♪ 它曾赠予我心爱的人 却又偷走了他 ♪
The curtain!
幕布
Close the curtain.
拉上幕布
Douglas, come here. Come here, please.
道格拉斯 过来 坐吧
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
That's why he needs you to support him.
这就是他需要你支持他的原因
So, you were a hit?
这么说, 你很受欢迎？
Well, let's not exaggerate.
不要太夸张了
I was sufficiently convincing for the boss
反正足以让老板信服
to hire me once a week, every Friday night.
每周五晚上雇我上台一次
I have to admit, I couldn't wait for Friday to come around.
我不得不承认, 我等不及周五的到来了
It was my only moment where my reflection
这是我的影子成功地
succeeded in making me forget my image.
让我忘记了自己形象的唯一时刻
So, the show was your only source of income?
所以, 演出是你唯一的收入来源？
No.
不
I was a kind of matchmaker.
我是一个媒人
I'd study the profile of the client
我会研究客户的情况
and suggest companions that had similar interests.
并建议兴趣相投的同伴
Your main activity was placing dogs in homes
你的主要活动是把狗送到那些
with people who were looking to break their solitude?
寄希望于它们能打破孤独的人的家里吗？
Yeah, mostly.
是的, 大部分
Mostly?
大部分？
What does that mean?
这是什么意思？
I also offered protection services.
我还提供保护服务
And how big were these protection services in your business plan?
这些保护服务在你的商业计划中占多大比重？
People want to be loved and protected.
人们希望得到关爱和保护
That's all anybody's praying for all day long.
这就是所有人整天在祈祷的东西
But I'm guessing the pay was nowhere near enough.
但我猜赚得还远远不够
You still needed money to rebuild and look after your dogs.
你仍然需要钱来重建家园和照顾你的狗
Well, the answer came from my dogs, actually.
其实, 答案来自我的狗
How? What do you mean?
怎么做？什么意思？
Not only were they my best friends, my most faithful companions,
他们不仅是我最好的朋友, 也是我最忠实的伴侣
but they also understood everything.
但他们也能理解每一件事
Absolutely everything I told them.
每一件我交待他们的事情
Plain flour?
普通面粉？
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm gonna need...
我需要...
250 grams unsalted butter.
Thank you.
谢谢
And two large eggs.
还有两个大鸡蛋
Thank you.
谢谢
Be a darling and fetch me some sugar.
可爱点, 给我拿点糖来
We're gonna make a very nice cake.
我们要做一个非常漂亮的蛋糕
I believe in the redistribution of wealth.
我相信财富的再分配
Do you know that the 100 richest people are richer than the poorest billion?
你知道吗, 前 100 位首富比最穷的十亿人还要富有？
Yes, I do.
是的, 我知道
It's outrageous, but that doesn't mean
这太离谱了, 但这并不意味着
that your actions are not against the law.
你的行为并不违法
Laws are written by the rich to control the poor.
法律是富人为控制穷人而制定的
It should be the other way around, don't you think?
应该反过来, 你说呢？
You're right.
你说得对
But that doesn't mean you get to be judge and jury.
但这并不意味着你可以成为法官和陪审团
I suppose you're right.
我想你是对的
I plead guilty.
我认罪
If you were earning a living, why continue stealing like that?
如果你在谋生, 为什么还要继续这样偷窃？
For the kids?
为了狗？
No. Far from it.
不 远非如此
I think that when society rejects a child, makes them an outcast,
我认为, 当社会排斥一个孩子, 让他们成为局外人,
they take everything that was never given to them as a way of making amends for the injustice.
他们就会拿走从未得到过的一切 作为弥补不公正的一种方式
Don't you think your explanation is just a play on words?
你不觉得你的解释只是在玩文字游戏吗？
I mean, a delinquent is a delinquent, right?
我的意思是, 罪犯就是罪犯, 对吗？
Nobody is born a delinquent.
没有人生来就是罪犯
You become one through circumstance.
他们变成罪犯只是因为境遇不同
God had wanted he could have made me
上帝如果愿意 他可以让我成为
a pianist, a florist, or a doctor, even.
一个钢琴家 花匠或甚至医生
Why didn't he?
为什么他没有？
Looking after dogs is just as good of a profession as any other
照顾狗和其他这些一样 也是一种很好的职业
Why are you continue the home invasions ?
为什么你要继续入室盗窃?
I stopped.
我停手了
A few months ago.
几个月前
What made you do that?
你为什么这么做？
A chance encounter.
一次偶遇
Qui es-tu?
你是?
Ackerman. Insurance.
阿克曼 保险公司的
Right this way.
这边请
Sir.
先生
Morning, ma'am.
早上好, 女士
Ackerman.
阿克曼
I'll be your claims adjuster for today.
我是你们今天的理赔员
Thank you for agreeing to see me.
谢谢你同意见我
Please take a seat.
请坐
OK.
好的
So what do you want to know?
你想知道什么？
Just, you know, tell me the whole story, I guess.
我想, 你知道的, 告诉我全部经过
Well, we came back from the United Nations gala
我们从联合国的晚宴回来
around 1 o'clock in the morning.
大概凌晨 1 点左右
I took off my necklace, put it on the dresser, as I always do.
我摘下项链, 像往常一样把它放在梳妆台上
Oh, not in the safe?
哦, 不在保险箱里？
Because I do believe that you have a safe, right?
因为你有一个保险箱, 对吗？
No, I was far too tired to come back down here.
不, 我太累了, 不想再下来了
I see.
我明白了
And the staff?
雇员呢？
What about the staff? Have they all left?
雇员呢？ 他们都走了吗？
Oh, long gone.
哦, 早就走了
I locked the front door myself.
我自己锁的前门
The dogs, you didn't hear the dogs bark last night?
狗, 你昨晚没听到狗叫吗？
No, not at all.
不, 完全没有
I'm a very light sleeper, too.
我睡眠也很浅
I would have heard them.
我会听到的
Was the window open?
窗户开着吗？
All the windows are tight shut.
所有窗户都关得严严实实
Well, except for one in the bathroom,
除了浴室里的一个
but it's far too small for anyone to get through.
但它太小了, 任何人都无法通过
I see.
我明白了
And, uh, what time did you realize the necklace was missing?
你是什么时候发现项链不见的？
When I woke up at 7 o'clock the next morning.
当我第二天早上 7 点钟醒来的时候
So... Okay, so let me get this straight.
那么....好吧, 让我理理清楚
So the jewelry vanished sometime between the hours of
因此, 珠宝是在 1 点到早上 7 点之间
1 and 7 in the morning from a locked house with you in it?
从你所在的上锁的房子里不见的？
Exactly.
没错
Now, if you think that I'm making this whole story up to cash in for the insurance...
现在, 如果你认为我编造这整个故事 是为了骗保费...
Well, far be it for me to suggest otherwise, ma'am.
我可不敢苟同 女士
Your reputation speaks for itself, but you have to admit
你的声誉不言而喻, 但你必须承认
it's a, you know, it's a tricky equation to square.
你知道, 这是一个难解的等式
Well, isn't that why you're here?
这不就是你来这里的原因吗？
Yes, indeed.
是的, 确实如此
As requested, the footage from the security cameras.
要求提供的, 监控摄像头的录像
There are 12 cameras all around this house.
房子周围有 12 个摄像头
None inside?
里面没有？
No.
没有
We appreciate our privacy.
我们很重视我们的隐私
Ma'am.
女士
♪ Que reste-t-il de nos amours? ♪
♪ 我们的爱情还剩下什么？ ♪
♪ Que reste-t-il de ces beaux jours? ♪
♪ 那些美好的日子还剩下什么？ ♪
♪ Une photo, vieille photo, ♪
♪ 一张照片, 一张老照片 ♪
♪ De ma jeunesse ♪
♪ 我的青春岁月 ♪
♪ Que reste-t-il Des billets doux ♪
♪ 甜美的音符还剩下什么？ ♪
♪ Des mois d'avril, des rendez-vous ♪
♪ 四月的约会 ♪
♪ Un souvenir qui me poursuit Sans cesse ♪
♪ 记忆如影随形 一遍又一遍 ♪
♪ Bonheur fané, cheveux au vent Baisers volés, rêves mouvants ♪
♪ 褪色的幸福 风中的秀发 偷来的吻 变幻的梦 ♪
1.04 a.m.
凌晨 1 点 04 分
A woman arrives home, and nothing till 7 in the morning when the maids arrive.
女人回到家后, 直到早上 7 点女佣来了, 什么情况也没有
Whoa, whoa.
哇哦 哇哦
Back it up a fraction.
倒回去一点
Back it up.
倒一点
What are they doing?
它们在做什么？
Looks like they're greeting someone.
他们好像在和谁打招呼
What's that?
那是什么？
Yeah, a stray dog enters the property,
是啊, 一只流浪狗闯进了这里,
they play for about five minutes, and then they takes off.
玩耍大约五分钟后, 他们就出去了
Go forward.
往前
Go frame by frame.
一帧一帧地看
Forward, forward.
前进, 前进
Right there.
就在那儿
There, the dog.
那只狗
See, it's got the necklace.
看, 它拿着项链
The dog's got the necklace.
项链在狗身上
It's hard to say for sure.
这很难确定
Could be its ID tag.
可能是它的身份标签
You get the tapes from last month, the burglary on Virginia Street?
你拿到上个月弗吉尼亚街盗窃案的录像带了吗？
Uh, yeah.
是的
Yeah.
有
Why don't you go get them, Jerry?
你为什么不去拿过来, 杰瑞？
Sure.
好
There.
在那儿
Go back. Back, back, back.
倒回去吧 倒 倒 倒
See? What did I tell you?
看到了吗？我怎么跟你说的？
There's another dog.
另一条狗
There's a dog right there.
那里有只狗
It's tough to call, sir.
这很难确定, 先生
Could be a fox.
可能是狐狸
They have a chicken run in the backyard.
他们的后院有一个鸡圈
Oh, is that what you think, Jerry?
哦, 你是这么想的吗, 杰瑞？
Why don't you go get the tapes related to similar cases?
你为什么不去把类似案件有关的录像带都拿来？
-Now, Jerry. -Yeah.
-现在, 杰瑞 -好
There.
那儿
See right there?
看到了吗？
See that?
Keep going.
往前
Oh, shit.
哦, 该死
See?
看到了吗？
Aha!
啊哈
This, my friend, this is the work of an artist.
朋友, 这是艺术家的所为
♪ Outside the barracks, by the corner light I'll always stand ♪
♪ 军营外, 角灯旁, 我永远伫立 ♪
♪ and wait for you at night We will create a world for two ♪
♪ 我们将创造一个二人世界 ♪
♪ I'll wait for you the whole night through. ♪
♪ 我会等你一整晚 ♪
♪ For you, Lily Marley. ♪
♪ 为了你, 莉莉·马利 ♪
♪ Bugler tonight, don't play the call to watch. ♪
♪ 今晚的号手, 请不要吹号观看 ♪
♪ I want another evening with a chance. ♪
♪ 我想再过一个有机会的夜晚 ♪
♪ Then we will say goodbye and pass. ♪
♪ 然后, 我们将道别并离开 ♪
♪ I'll always keep you in my heart. ♪
♪ 我会永远把你放在心里 ♪
♪ With me, Lily Marley. ♪
♪ 和我一起, 莉莉·马利 ♪
♪ Give me a rose to show how much you care. ♪
♪ 给我一朵玫瑰, 表示你有多在乎我 ♪
♪ Tie to the stem a lock of golden hair. ♪
♪ 在茎干上绑上一绺金发 ♪
♪ Surely tomorrow you'll feel blue, ♪
♪ 明天你肯定会感到忧郁 ♪
♪ but then will come a love that's new. ♪
♪ 但随之而来的将是全新的爱 ♪
♪ For you, Lily Marley. ♪
♪ 为了你, 莉莉·马利 ♪
姓名：道格拉斯·蒙罗
住址：未知
♪ It's you, Lily Marley. ♪
♪ 是你, 莉莉・马利 ♪
-You were so good. -It was so good.
-你太棒了 -太棒了
-You looked fantastic. -You looked beautiful.
-你看起来棒极了 -你看起来真美
I am so proud of you.
我真为你感到骄傲
Girls, are you decent? Good.
姑娘们, 注意影响 很好
Marlena, darling, you have a gentleman caller.
玛莲娜, 亲爱的, 有位先生找你
She's got fans now.
她现在有粉丝了
Hello.
你好
Hi. Sorry. I just wanted to congratulate you.
你好 对不起 我只是想祝贺你
Wow. That was awesome.
哇 太精彩了
I'm a total fan.
我是你的忠实粉丝
Thank you.
谢谢
Yeah.
嗯
May I? Sorry. May I?
可以吗？对不起 可以吗？
Yeah.
是啊
My mother's family came from Germany, so I know all those songs by heart.
我母亲的家族就是德国来的, 所以这些歌曲我都烂熟于心
And believe me when I say you gave a magnificent rendition.
相信我, 你的演绎非常精彩
Well, coming from a specialist, I appreciate the compliment even more.
嗯 来自专家的赞美让我更加感激
Perform every night?
每晚都表演？
No, once a week.
不, 一周一次
Oh, good call.
哦, 不错的选择
Yeah, you know, the rarer something is, the greater its value.
是的, 你知道, 越稀有的东西价值越高
It's true.
这是真的
Which night?
哪个晚上？
Friday.
星期五
Now you know where to find me every Friday night.
现在你知道每周五晚上在哪里能找到我了
Look, I know this is rather, uh, bold, but...
听着, 我知道这很大胆, 但是...
May I invite you to dinner with me?
我能邀请你和我共进晚餐吗？
I'm just dying to get to know you.
我只是很想认识你
You already know the best part of me, darling.
你已经认识我最好的一面了, 亲爱的
The rest isn't worth wasting your time on.
其他的就不值得浪费时间了
Ah, you are much too modest, like all true artistes.
啊, 你太谦虚了, 像所有真正的艺术家一样
I don't know what you do for a living,
我不知道你是做什么职业的
sir, but you'd make one hell of a salesman.
先生, 但你会成为一个出色的推销员
I work in insurance.
我干保险的
That makes sense. They're the worst.
这就说得通了 他们是最糟糕的
When you're right, you're right.
当你是对的, 就无可争议
You are so right.
你说得太对了
But, you know, under the suit, there's a man.
但是, 你知道, 在这套西装下面, 是一个男人
A man worth getting to know.
一个值得认识的男人
I'm sure.
我确定
Or worth getting dinner with, at least.
或者至少值得共进晚餐
Come on.
来吧
Have dinner with me. I know you want to have dinner with me.
和我共进晚餐吧 我知道你想和我共进晚餐
That's very sweet of you.
你真好
And I appreciate the offer.
我很感谢你的邀请
But I need to get home.
但我必须回家
I have my children to feed.
我还要喂我的孩子
I hope you understand.
希望你能理解
Well, apologies if I came on a little strong.
好吧, 如果我表现得有点过头, 请原谅
No, not at all.
不, 一点也不
But I will see you next Friday?
下周五见？
With pleasure.
乐意之至
Yeah.
是啊
Whoa.
哇哦
It's just, you just, you made my night.
你让我度过了一个美好的夜晚
What was that?
那是怎么回事？
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
-Is it real? -Yes.
-是真花吗？-是的
How often does that happen to you?
你经常遇到这种情况吗？
Well, quite often.
嗯, 经常这样
You sure you got the right address?
你确定地址没错吗？
It's just a shortcut.
这是条近路
I just need a little fresh air.
我只是需要一点新鲜空气
Think you could help me with my chair, please?
你能帮我搬一下椅子吗？
Sure.
当然
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey, what's up?
嘿, 怎么了？
Okay, good luck.
好吧 祝你好运
Kids, get ready.
孩子们, 准备好了
We have company.
我们有伴了
Well, I admire your persistence, sir.
我很佩服你的坚持, 先生
This is verging on harassment.
这简直就是骚扰
-I could sue for this. - Oh, be my guest, pal.
-我可以告你的 -哦, 请便, 朋友
I'll tell the court about your dogs that you trained to steal from houses.
我会告诉法庭你训练狗偷东西的事
My dogs are as free as the air you breathe, sir.
我的狗就像你呼吸的空气一样自由, 先生
They've received no particular training from me, I assure you.
我向你保证, 他们没有接受过我的特别训练
I have several dozen videos that prove the opposite,
我有几十个视频可以证明相反的情况
and some of the protagonists live in this very room.
其中一些主角就住在这个房间里
I also have a list of all the valuables that were stolen,
我还有一份被盗的所有贵重物品的清单
jewelry mostly, which you have no hesitation flaunting on stage.
主要是珠宝, 你毫不犹豫想要在舞台上炫耀的那些
That's cute, but I don't steal.
很可爱, 但我不偷东西
I contribute to the redistribution of wealth.
我在为财富的再分配做出贡献
Very different things.
两码事
Fine by me, but let's redistribute it differently.
我没意见, 但让我们以不同的方式再重新分配一下
Okay? If you don't mind.
好吗？如果你不介意的话
Oh, so it's all about money.
哦, 原来都是为了钱
Uh, yes!
是的
It's all about money!
一切都是为了钱！
Money, money, money.
钱 钱 钱
Always sunny in the...
总是阳光明媚的...
Honey, whatever the fuck you are, the show is over, okay?
亲爱的, 无论你是他妈的什么玩意, 演出结束了, 好吗？
You're gonna hand over the rocks
你要交出宝石
that you must have stashed somewhere in all this mess.
你肯定把宝石藏在了这里的某个地方
Do not try telling me that they're in a bank, because you have zero accounts.
不要想骗我说在银行里, 因为你没有任何账户
I checked.
我查过了
Don't fuck with me.
别耍我
Give me the fucking rocks.
把该死的宝石给我
I really do not want to shoot a handicapped person today,
我今天真的不想对残疾人开枪
but I fucking will.
但他妈的别逼我
70, 80, 70.
70, 80, what is that?
What are these numbers?
It's my vital statistics
这是我的三围数据
and the combination to the safe over there in the closet.
和柜子里保险箱的密码
Oh, fuck yes.
哦, 他妈的太好了
Now that you're a rich man, I'd be happy to accept your dinner invitation.
现在你是个有钱人了, 我很乐意接受你的晚餐邀请
Take a seat. Dinner will be ready in two minutes.
请坐 晚餐将在两分钟内准备好
You want to have dinner with me?
你想和我共进晚餐吗？
Sure.
当然
Why wouldn't I?
为什么不呢？
I mean, to be completely honest, it's not very often that I get visitors.
老实说, 我这里并不经常会有访客来
Besides, money has never been what drives me, and all those necklaces
此外, 钱从来都不是我的动力, 那些项链
would definitely get more use around the necks of pretty ladies.
戴在美女的脖子上肯定会更有用
You're insane.
你疯了
Thank you.
谢谢
Take a seat.
请坐
Do you like chili?
你喜欢辣椒吗？
Well, you know, it depends.
嗯, 你知道, 这要看情况
My mother used to make it all the time.
我妈妈以前经常做这个
I used to love watching her cook.
我以前很喜欢看她做饭
To be honest, I'm so hungry I could eat a horse.
说实话, 我饿得能吃下一匹马
That's lucky. It's ready.
真幸运 晚餐准备好了
You are aware that we're talking
你知道我们在谈论
about a serious criminal act here, right?
严重的犯罪行为, 对吗？
Dog eat dog.
狗咬狗
It's just a simple law of nature, isn't it?
这只是一个简单的自然规律, 不是吗？
You know, my profession demands the strictest
你知道, 我的职业要求
confidentiality with regards to our discussions.
对我们的讨论严格保密
Should I, however, be witness even indirectly to a criminal act that resulted in a death,
然而, 如果我是导致死亡的犯罪行为的间接证人
I am legally obligated to report any information that I may have.
我有法律义务报告我可能掌握的任何信息
I'll plead self-defense.
我会辩护为自卫
You risk the death penalty.
你有可能被判处死刑的
You realize that?
你知道吗？
I've already died several times.
我已经死过好几次了
This one could be the last.
这可能是最后一次了
Well, if it's God's will.
好吧, 如果这是上帝的旨意
At the end of the day, I'm just a puppet at the end of his strings.
说到底, 我只是被他操纵着的一个傀儡
No, you're not.
不, 你不是
Things happen in life, true,
人生不如意十之八九 没错
and most of the time, there's nothing you can do about it.
大部分时间, 你对此无能为力
Ultimately, it's our reaction that matters the most.
归根结底, 我们要如何面对才是最重要的
I mean, you can be sad.
我是说, 你可以悲伤
You can be desperate.
你可以绝望
You could fight or you could laugh about it.
你可以反抗, 也可以一笑置之
It's really up to you.
这完全取决于你
It's your decision. No one else's.
这是你的决定 不是别人的
It's called free will.
这就是所谓的自由意志
God invented it.
上帝发明的
How often did this type of situation happen?
这种情况经常发生吗？
Which kind of situation?
哪种情况？
Killing a man.
杀人
No, not until yesterday.
没有, 直到昨天才有
What happened yesterday?
昨天发生了什么？
God sent his angels of the apocalypse.
上帝派来了他的末日天使们
♪ I want to be loved by you, just you. ♪
♪ 我想被你爱, 只有你 ♪
♪ Nobody else but you. ♪
♪ 除了你, 没有别人 ♪
♪ I wanna be loved by you alone. ♪
♪ 我只想被你一个人爱 ♪
♪ I wanna be kissed by you just you. ♪
♪ 我只想被你吻 只有你 ♪
♪ Nobody else but you. ♪
♪ 除了你, 没有别人 ♪
♪ I wanna be kissed by you alone. ♪
♪ 我想被你一个人亲吻 ♪
No! Please! Please! No!
别 求求你 别
♪ ... anything higher ♪
♪ ...更高的追求 ♪
♪ Than to feel the desire ♪
♪ 只想让你 ♪
♪ To make you my own, Ba-dum-ba-dum-ba-doodly-dum-boo! ♪
♪ 成为我的爱人... ♪
♪ I want to be loved by you, just you. ♪
♪ 我想被你爱, 只有你 ♪
♪ Nobody else but you. ♪
♪ 除了你, 没有别人 ♪
♪ I wanna be loved by you alone. ♪
♪ 我只想被你一个人爱 ♪
Are you sure he lives here?
你确定他住在这里？
Yes, yes, yes, I swear to God.
是的, 是的, 我对天发誓
I swear to God. He is there at the end of the hallway.
我对天发誓 他就在走廊尽头
with his dogs.
和狗一起
Okay, I believe you.
好吧, 我相信你
Now, find me this motherfucker.
现在, 给我抓住这个混蛋
Come on, let's go.
来吧, 我们走
Time for war, everyone.
开战了, 各位
What's up?
怎么了？
The fucking dogs
该死的狗
Go check, go check.
去看看, 去看看
Mierda.
米尔达
Go around, go around.
绕过去, 绕过去
Okay, yo por aqui. Tu por alla.
好 我走这边 你走那边
Okay, okay.
好吧 好吧
Vamos.
我们走
This is it.
就是这里
Fuck you, dog.
操你妈 狗
Damn! Are you okay?
该死 你还好吗？
Rico!
里科
Bring me the artillery.
给我大炮
It's over, kid.
结束了, 孩子
We had a deal.
我们说好的
I thought we had a deal!
我以为我们谈妥了
But as we've known for so long,
但正如我们早已知道的
these are just sentiments that lead to a person's downfall.
能导致一个人崩溃的 就只有情绪
You're the devil.
你是魔鬼
I'm sending you back to hell.
我要把你送回地狱
If it's God's will.
如果这是上帝的旨意
I guess God is not on your side today.
我猜上帝今天没站在你这边
Cheers.
干杯
Thank you.
谢谢
That's a cute lighter.
那打火机真可爱
Wanna keep it?
想留着它吗？
Sure.
当然
Thank you. Sir.
谢谢 警官
It's ridiculous.
太荒谬了
Are all those dogs yours?
这些狗都是你的吗？
Yes, they're my babies.
是的, 他们是我的宝贝
I don't know what they're going to do with them.
我不知道他们会怎么处理它们
Don't worry. They know exactly what to do.
别担心 它们完全知道该怎么做
I think I've asked enough questions for today.
我想我今天问得够多了
I'm gonna take some time and process all of this
我要花点时间来处理这一切
and figure out how I can... how I can help you.
找出....我怎么才能帮助你的办法
That's very sweet of you.
你真好
And you've already helped me a lot, actually.
事实上, 你已经帮了我很多
You're right.
你说得对
I need to make a decision about my life.
我的人生应该由我来决定
Perhaps I have to pay the ultimate price
也许我必须付出生命的代价
to earn the right to be by his side.
才能赢得回到他身旁的权利
Today is Sunday.
今天是星期天
It's the Lord's day.
是主日
The right day to ask him this question.
正是问他这个问题的好日子
Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢你, 医生
Evelyn.
艾芙琳
Thank you, Evelyn.
谢谢你, 艾芙琳
Can I ask you one more question?
我能再问你一个问题吗？
Sure.
当然
What made you open up to me?
为什么你会对我敞开心扉？
We both have something in common.
我们有一些共同点
Yeah, what's that?
是什么？
Pain.
痛苦
Are you done?
你好了吗
Yes.
是的
I'm done.
好了
No, no, no.
不, 不, 不
Hey, guys.
嘿, 伙计们
Okay, it's time to go
好 该走了
♪ Non, rien de rien, Non, je ne regrette rien ♪
♪ 不, 我一点也不后悔, 不, 我不后悔 ♪
♪ Ni le bien qu'on m'a fait, Ni le mal où ça m'est bien aidé ♪
♪ 既不后悔我的善心, 也不后悔我的恶行, 我不在乎 ♪
♪ Non, rien de rien, ♪
♪ 不 我一点也不后悔 ♪
♪ No, je ne regrette rien ♪
♪ 不 我不后悔 ♪
♪ C'est payé, balayé, oublié Je ♪
♪ 我付过了代价, 烟消云散, 就全忘了吧 ♪
♪ le me fous du passé, Avec mes souvenirs, J'ai allumé le feu ♪
♪ 我不在乎过去 我用记忆 点燃了火焰 ♪
♪ Mes chagrins, mes plaisirs, Je n'ai plus besoin d'eux ♪
♪ 我的悲伤 我的快乐 都不需要 ♪
♪ Balayé les amours... ♪
♪ 把爱都带走... ♪
Here I am.
我来了
For you.
等你
I am standing for you.
我站着等你
I am standing for you!
♪ Non, rien de rien, Non, je ne regrette rien ♪
♪ 不, 我一点也不后悔, 不, 我不后悔 ♪
♪ Ni le bien qu'on m'a fait, Ni le mal où ça m'est bien égal ♪
♪ 既不后悔我的善心, 也不后悔我的恶行, 无关紧要 ♪
I'm ready.
我准备好了
♪ Non, rien de rien, Non, je ne regrette rien ♪
♪ 不, 我一点也不后悔, 不, 我不后悔 ♪
♪ Car ma vie, car mes joies, Aujourd' hui... ça commence avec toi! ♪
♪ 为了我的生活, 为了我的快乐, 今天....从你开始... ♪
《狗 神》
字幕:Dex7er 公众号:值得看的
♪ Autumn star ♪
♪ 秋日的星星 ♪
♪ All by herself she is ♪
♪ 她只身一人 ♪
♪ Hoping for more ♪
♪ 渴望更多 ♪
♪ Her own arms around her ♪
♪ 她用双臂环抱着自己 ♪
♪ Let us throw effortlessly in a dream ♪
♪ 让我们毫不费力地进入梦乡 ♪
♪ Be The comfort that I need ♪
♪ 成为我所需要的慰藉 ♪
♪ Give me the illusion that I like ♪
♪ 给我我喜欢的幻觉 ♪
♪ Make me believe ♪
♪ 使我相信 ♪
♪ Autumn star ♪
♪ 秋日的星星 ♪
♪ The loneliest one of all ♪
♪ 夜空中最孤寂的那一颗 ♪
♪ Venus ♪
♪ 维纳斯 ♪
♪ She needs someone to hold her ♪
♪ 她需要一个人紧紧拥抱她 ♪
♪ Let us throw effortlessly in a dream ♪
♪ 让我们毫不费力地进入梦乡 ♪
♪ Be the comfort that I need ♪
♪ 成为我所需要的慰藉 ♪
♪ Give me the illusion that I like ♪
♪ 给我我喜欢的幻觉 ♪
♪ Make me believe ♪
♪ 使我相信 ♪
♪ There’s more to this life ♪
♪ 这生命中有更重要的东西 ♪
♪ I know to love that doesn’t make me pay ♪
♪ 我知道去爱它没有让我付出代价 ♪
♪ All of broken ♪
♪ 一切破碎 ♪
♪ Conducting love beautiful as a ballet ♪
♪ 让爱翩翩起舞如芭蕾般美丽 ♪
♪ Ending, ruing ♪
♪ 结束, 后悔 ♪
♪ Autumn star ♪
♪ 秋日的星星 ♪
♪ all by herself she is ♪
♪ 她只身一人 ♪
♪ hoping for more ♪
♪ 渴望更多 ♪
♪ Her own arms around her ♪
♪ 她用双臂环抱着自己 ♪
♪ Let us throw effortlessly in a dream ♪
♪ 让我们毫不费力地进入梦乡 ♪
♪ Be the comfort that I need ♪
♪ 成为我所需要的慰藉 ♪